planningcenteronline.com 2016-06-25

# Privacy Policy | Planning Center Online

Ministry Centered Technologies collects user information in a manner consistent with the laws of the countries in which it does business. The information that may be collected includes, but is not limited to, email addresses, website history, survey information and website registrations. 

The information Ministry Centered Technologies collects is used to improve the content of Ministry Centered Technologies’ Web pages and the quality of Ministry Centered Technologies’ service.User information is not shared with or sold to other organizations for commercial purposes, except to provide products or services the user has requested, when the user has given Ministry Centered Technologies permission to share such information, or under the following circumstances: 

Ministry Centered Technologies may disclose personal data, including the data users submit to Ministry Centered Technologies, with or without notice if (a) required by a subpoena or other judicial or administrative order, (b) where required by law, or (c) at Ministry Centered Technologies’ sole discretion, where deemed necessary to protect the safety of any individual, the general public, or to prevent violation of Ministry Centered Technologies’ Terms Of Service. 

In the event of a change in ownership, or a direct merger or acquisition with another entity, Ministry Centered Technologies reserves the right to transfer all of Ministry Centered Technologies’ user information to a separate entity. In this event, Ministry Centered Technologies will notify its users when user information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. 

When a user registers for any one of the Ministry Centered Technologies services, Ministry Centered Technologies must ask for information, such as the user’s name, company name, email address, billing address, and/or credit card information. Members who sign up for the free account are not required to enter credit card information. 

Ministry Centered Technologies uses collected information for the following general purposes: products and services provision, billing, identification and authentication, services improvement, contact, and research. 

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier, that is sent to the user’s browser from a web site’s computers and stored on the user’s computer hard drive. 

Ministry Centered Technologies service requires the use of cookies. 

Ministry Centered Technologies uses cookies to record current session information, but do not use permanent cookies. Users are required to log-in to their Ministry Centered Technologies Site after a certain period of time has elapsed to protect against others accidentally accessing their account contents. 

Although Ministry Centered Technologies owns the data storage, databases and all rights to the Planning Center application, its users retain all rights to their data. Ministry Centered Technologies will never sell or share user client data with any third parties, contact the user’s clients directly, or use its users’ data for its own business advantage. Ministry Centered Technologies will also not utilize user data in its database to compete with its users, market to its users’ clients, or advertise or contact its users’ clients for any other means of profit. Ministry Centered Technologies respects the privacy of its users, and the privacy of its user’s client data. 

Ministry Centered Technologies employs a self-assessment approach to maintain compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, prominently displayed, adequately implemented, and accessible to its users.  Ministry Centered Technologies encourages interested persons to raise any concerns by contacting Ministry Centered Technologies at the address listed below. Ministry Centered Technologies will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding its use and disclosure of user information in conformity with its privacy policy. 

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, Ministry Centered Technologies commits to resolve complaints about its users’ privacy and its use and/or collection of users’ personal information.  European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Ministry Centered Technologies at the address listed below. 

Ministry Centered Technologies has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the International Center for Dispute Resolution, operated by the American Arbitration Association. Individuals whose concerns have been adequately addressed by Ministry Centered Technologies can obtain further information about international dispute resolution at [http://www.icdr.org/.](http://www.icdr.org/)

Ministry Centered Technologies complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Ministry Centered Technologies has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Ministry Centered Technologies’ certification, please visit  [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/.](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/)

Ministry Centered Technologies may periodically update this policy. Ministry Centered Technologies will notify its users about significant changes to its Privacy Policy by sending a notice to the user’s primary email address listed with Ministry Centered Technologies, or by placing a prominent notice on its website. 

Any questions about this Privacy Policy should be addressed to our support team here or by mail at:
